so what types of shared memory hardware
do we have we can have multiple
single cores
that share the same physical address
space so all of them can issue addresses
to any memory address and the examples
we have seen of this are the yuma and
numa both of them actually are
individual cores each of them
being able to access the entire address
space
the other extreme is to only have one
core
and then do multi-threading
basically run two threads by just time
sharing the same core so because they're
now running really on the same core they
are naturally accessing the same
physical memory so we get the shared
memory behavior simply by virtue of
actually not having more than one core
and now the question is is there
something in between them because this
is not really capable of benefiting from
having multi-threading we can have
hardware multi-threading support in one
core that actually tries to benefit from
there being multiple threads
this hardware multi-threading can be at
a coarse grain
where we change the thread we are
working on every few cycles
and we now need to have harder support
that switches between threads
this often because without hardware
support
we would be spending all of the time
just saving and restoring registers of
these threads so we actually need to now
have every thread has its own set of
hardware registers and so on so there is
hardware support needed for this we can
have fine grain hardware multi-threading
where every cycle we are working on
another thread
this of course needs even more harder
support because now we need to be able
to very quickly change between these
threads
and we can also have
simultaneous multi-threading or smt
where in any given cycle we could be
doing instructions that belong to these
different threads this is called
simultaneous multi-threading or smt
and it's also called hyper threading by
some manufacturers of processors so now
we need hardware support for any one of
these three and of course the hardware
support becomes more extensive as we
move from coarse grain to fine grain to
simultaneous so the question is but what
do we benefit by kind of sharing the
same core
by multiple threads don't we get the
same thing as here